[Music]
w
hello everybody Welcome to ask abijit
episode 173 it's great to be back among
you all live on this live stream it's
great to see your smiling faces I hope
you're smiling I'm smiling so let's see
who all is there on the live stream I
can see Mato Perez from Texas kulp
Sharma inderjit vivanda Redi Anonymous
watching from Nigeria hello sir ma'am
RNA Justice warrior 24 by7 Sachin Kumar
pram priyan sud hello Yash laan
bhatnagar Sak Singh Sumit Kumar sakam
Valia meul threeways to deos man Das
Gupta Sid
Rohan kov vdash dongar sing Chan Welcome
Back Sir anur Singh Jil HTI bjack
Horseman sidart rajit feminist sler Vin
esman
sidhant uh golden Yogi anur Singh asde
Singh geopolitical du hello uh lots of
other people let's see lots lots lots
lots lots I can see Sachin giri Ashu
nagra Samar T anonymous sidhant nikum
Mukesh boy 21 zubon ising Rahul Singh
jay van paria technical advisor himansu
Sharma Ajit anit aders dantu dantu
Prashant Nesh Patel Satish tmai Hari
hello Ram swar yashwant Neil Lan NJ Oma
CP Varma sonat MN B Suzie two wats 2K
wats crazy brain
uh jatin
trudo uh any Master winged Star Travel
videos YK pratus ADI Gupta bries IC
Ranjit Chri and so many other people I
will not be able to greet you all
individually let me try some more crazy
brain Amit
hya Nan VI tanai Rog gamer mures Dutch
wonderer Lind Akash mayang the P himansu
mul rajes Babu and everybody else so
thank you all for being on the live
stream it's great to be back live on
episode
173 and uh before we begin let me once
again remind you that I have launched a
geopolitics course and you can check it
out it's the link is in the description
below so why have I created this course
it's because everything I do I believe
in thinking differently I believe in
challenging the status quo and the way I
challenge the status quo is by making
these videos and doing these live
streams and giving you a realistic view
of the world I give you a different view
of the world not the view that TV
channels and news readers and YouTubers
and other analysts give you I give you a
different view of the world which is a
more realistic view I believe in
excellence I keep on saying raise your
standards and based on these values I
have created a geopolitics course based
on my analytical framework it's called
geopolitics from first principles and uh
check out the link in the description
it's only for people who are serious
about learning geopolitics so check it
out I'll put the link in the chat as
well if you want to see that and with
that said let me uh
start taking questions so let's see what
questions we have I had seen a few good
questions let me see all right let's
begin with this this is by by Dia so Dia
says why didn't Iran invade India you
didn't answer this question in previous
ask Abit live stream you kept it
suspense okay that's a good question so
yes so first of all I hope all of us
know where Iran is located in case some
of us don't know let's go to the map
where is the map we have to see the map
to understand where this nation this
civilization Persia is located so it's
our neighboring well it used to be our
neighboring country right now we have
this temporary Nation between Iran and
India which is Pakistan matter of time
so Persia is historically has been the
civilization west of India and uh so
that's that's Iran all right and uh if
we go back into if you go back in time
then we will see that Persian history
begins about three and a half thousand
years before today we have the H Hamish
Dynasty the cabinet Dynasty that ruled
Persia it was a great uh militaristic
Dynasty it was an expans anist Dynasty
and then we had other kings and
dynasties also that followed in its
footsteps and historically if we see the
persan military activities their
military expansions they were all
westwards they fought essentially the
Greeks and eventually the Romans and
well if you look at a further larger
view of History then eventually they
fought the Arabs and they were conquered
by the Arabs which Begins the chapter of
the islamization of Persia but
historically they
fought the Greeks and later the Romans
after the Romans conquered Greece so
they always expanded
westwards and east of Persia we had
India and India at times was unified
under under a single Empire and at times
India was fragmented into lots of
different kingdoms but the same
civilization the same
culture so the question is why did the
Persians never
ever think of invading India and some of
you will say that n invaded India well
nadisha nadisha he was a Turk and that's
a much later episode just the last 2 300
years 400 whatever it is you can check
out the date right nadash Sha was a Turk
he was not a Persian and this happened
after the islamization of Persia after
the Arabs invaded and converted all of
Persia to their religion okay so before
the islamization of Persia Persia never
ever tried to invade India that's the
point
and the question is a very good question
why did they never do that even though
they were so expansionist they had these
expansionist Tendencies they were a
powerful Empire and so on why did they
not invade India they didn't even
attempt to invade India why is that so
to answer that I have to show you a few
things so let me put something else on
the screen let me offer you offer you
some Clues and based on the clues we'll
draw some
conclusions so this is a YouTube channel
by a music musician called Faria faraji
okay now lots of ancient music that he
recreates he or she I think it's he okay
now let's search for
vaham on this channel and there is this
song this YouTube video It's a song it's
called The Ballad of King vaham now I
can't play this over here because it'll
give me a copyright strike or whatever
because it's it's proprietary music so I
won't play this but I would encourage
you to check out this channel play this
video and see the lyrics the translation
into English if you want a translation
let me offer you a translation so uh
this is a research
paper that was published in 1955 it's by
JC tavad I believe that person is Pary
Indian Pary Indian portion and it's
about that particular song okay it's a
it's a song in the pavi language and
this song was written right after in the
aftermath of the Arabic invasion of
Persia after the the Persian kings were
destroyed and the culture was destroyed
and they started imposing their religion
on Persia so this song was written in
the aftermath of the Arabic
Invasion and and conquest of Persia now
let's take a look at the actual text let
me put that on the screen because I have
uh the actual research paper not just
the abstract I have the whole
thing let us Igan the size of this thing
okay so yeah this is the the whole thing
now let's go to the text this is the
Persian text which is the pal
text and they have the English
translation the translation is that when
may it be that a ker comes from India
and says that the Shah vaham from the
family of the P has come that there are
a thousand elephants upon their heads
are elephant Keepers and that he ra
holds the raised standard in the manner
of the host ofas so it is saying the the
lyrics say that the writer wish es that
a ker comes from India and says that the
Shah vaham from India has come with a
thousand elephants to rescue Persia from
the Arabs okay and so it says further an
intelligent man should be made our
clever interpreter who may go and speak
to the Indians namely see what has I
mean I'll not go into the exact details
what we have seen from the hands of the
Arabs they have ruined the religion and
killed the Kings and and so on and so
forth we are from the arest they are the
Arabs are the Divas which means in the
in the Z tradition the dasas are the bad
guys like we for us the dasas are the
good guys and the asuras the bad guys in
zor trism it is inverted but you know
what they mean so essentially this song
says that we should send a clever
interpreter to India and inform the
Indians of what has been done to us what
has happened to us the Arabs have come
and destroyed our religion our culture
they've killed our Kings and they have
ruined the nation and so so on they have
taken away the sovereignty from the h
not by skitt but by Whatever by not by
skill not by manliness they have made
mockery and Scorn they have taken away
by force from men their wives and their
wealth and their sweet palaces Parks
Gardens they have imposed a tax okay a
certain tax and so on so the
Persians whoever wrote this song that
person wishes that we we can persans can
send a messenger to the Indians and tell
them what's happened to us and clearly
this me this writer believes that if the
Indians come to know what's happened
they will come and rescue us so what
does that tell you and this happened
this song was written in the pahal
language in the aftermath of the Arabic
invasion of Persia that's about how many
years ago 1300 years ago roughly roughly
give or take you can check out when it
happened look it up Google it or
wherever
right so even 1300 years ago the
Persians believed that if a message
would go to the Indians and the Indians
would come with 10,000 thousand
elephants and a huge Army and they would
rescue Persia from the Arabs what that
tells you is that the Persians saw
Indians as their kin as their own
people as family you understand and he
also mentions that we are from the Arya
stock the Arian stock the translation
into English is Arian but the correct
term is Arya and the Persians viewed
this term Arya as an ethnic term we
Indians viewed this as a as a sign of
nobility nobility as a noble Behavior
you know Arya means a person who is
civilized that's all it meant it was not
ethnic for us but for the persans who
had left India long long ago and settled
to the West for them it was an ethnic
term so that's the deal the Persians saw
India as their Indians as as their kin
they saw India as family and when you
are family you don't fight right you
don't invade family you invade the
others to the West so this song it's
very obscure almost no one knows about
this but it's really interesting and it
tells you a lot about the ancient
relationship between Persia and India
before the islamization of Persia and
after the islamization of Persia lots of
things changed in Persia even the uh
ethnic mix the ethnic makeup of the
Persian people of Persia changed okay
today you will see in Persia if you go
to Iran you will see lots of people not
lots but significant amount of
people who have very light skin who have
green or blue eyes you will see people
who have blonde hair not lots but a
few those are people who were brought
into Persia from the Caucasus region
during the turkic rule or Persia let me
once again go to the map okay this is
interesting thing so if you look at the
map here's the map so we have Persia or
Iran and Northwest of Persia we have the
Caucasus region which is the region
between the Black Sea and the Caspian
Sea okay this see this is the Caspian
Sea here in the middle of this the
screen and to the left of the screen you
have the Black Sea the region between
these two Seas roughly is the C is is
the Caucasus region and lots of people
were settled from the Caucasus region
into Persia by the Turks
right so that changed the ethnic makeup
of Persia if you look at Persia today
and if you look at the ethnic groups
within Persia you will find that the
actual Persians are roughly about 50% of
the population of Persia and the rest
are other ethnicities like the aaran
Aeris the Arabs and so on and so forth
balois also and so on so only half of
Persia today is actually Persian and a
lot of a lot of this similar to what
happened in Afghanistan today if you
look at the ethnic makeup of Afghanistan
uh the majority people are still the
pashun the pakun okay but there are lots
of other ethnic groups who have come in
after the invasion of Afghanistan of of
gandhar which turned gandhar into
Afghanistan all right so yeah that's the
story so to make a long story short to
answer the question that DIA has asked
the Persians never ever fought India
they never tried to invade India because
they saw India as their own people they
saw India as the probably the ancient
Homeland and you don't fight family you
don't fight uh you do fight family but
they chose not to ever because they had
lots of opportunities to expand
westwards and why why not go there fight
the Greeks fight the Romans and take
their
lands I mean once again go going to the
map going back to the map you will see
that the Persians they they they
expanded Westward significantly the
whole of what is today turkey which was
then Greece was at one point in time
taken over by the king k
zeris and yeah he well he fought battles
all the way in Greece Battle of thermop
where a number of Spartans fought the
Persians and so on so that's why the
Persians chose to fight the Greeks and
the westerners the ionians the yavanas
and not the Indians to make a long story
short all right let's take a different
question kulp Sharma says what's the
reason for the similarity of the
historical culture of the mitani Empire
with Indian culture what does it
indicate okay the mitani once again
let's go to the map as always map map
map map tells you everything it tells
you a lot doesn't tell you everything
but it tells you a lot so where is bhat
bhat is here we all know where it is
let's go westwards westwards let's cross
the temporary Nation let's go across
gandar Let's cross Persia and let's go
into
Mesopotamia and over here we have the
present day nation of turkey which was
historically Greek and Armenian and
somewhere here we had the ancient mitani
Kingdom right and the mitani well they
spoke the H the manani language hurrian
language whatever it was and they had
the uniform script but it it emerges it
emerges because of evidence that we have
found archaeological evidence that the
aristocracy the ruling class of the
mitani they spoke a different language
they spoke Sanskrit and how do we know
this well there was a horse Master
called Kuli okay he wrote a detailed
horse training manual which is still
available which can still be used by the
way to train battle horses so he wrote a
detailed horse training manual in the
local language but there were certain
terms that were not available in the
local language because that language was
not evolved enough so he was forced to
use his own native language for those
terms those technical terms those terms
he wrote in Sanskrit and that is
strangely enough the oldest evidence
that we have of written Sanskrit
anywhere in the world even older than
what we find in India in India we
probably wrote on perishable surfaces
birch bark or or you know Palm leaves or
maybe some form of cloth or whatever so
the oldest evidence of written Sanskrit
is from this region and if you analyze
the Sanskrit that they used you will
find that it is late Vic Sanskrit not
rig VC Sanskrit not old not early Vic
Sanskrit it is late Vic Sanskrit which
tells you that that they probably most
likely went westwards out of India and
there are other there's lots of evidence
that points towards various migrations
Westward out of India one of them is the
bodana Sutra which you which I invite
you which I encourage you to go check
out the
bod Sutra and so on so the reason for
the similarity of the historical culture
of the metanis with Indian culture is
because they most likely migrants out of
India who went all the way westwards and
settled over here between Syria and
Anatolia or present day Turkey and you
find their treaties okay they had these
alliances and treaties with neighboring
kingdoms the mitani and the Hittites for
example in which they inv invoke the Vic
Gods Mitra varuna and so on so forth
okay as as as witnesses to the
treaty and there's so much more evidence
I I could speak for hours but yeah there
you go so the reason for the similarity
is that they were migrants out of India
and there's plenty of evidence of
migration out of India and westwards and
northwestwards starting from the very
beginning of the Vic age which is the
Battle of the 10 Kings all
right okay
um okay let's see some other
questions what's the ancient history of
Israel I mean if I start with the
ancient history of Israel I could talk
for at least
Nar but to condense it very short into
into something very small and very brief
okay once again I should go to the map
where is Israel I hope you all know
where it is but let's anyway check it
out where is Israel so Israel is this
nation on the Eastern banks of the
Mediterranean Sea ancient Nation ancient
culture okay so the Israeli people the
the Jewish people uh their history goes
back about 3,000 years okay uh the
oldest uh
archaeological written evidence for for
Hebrew people or Jewish people I think
it's about 3,000 or so years old and
then we have Kings like King Saul King
David King Solomon Etc which who all
lived in
the first half of the first millennium
BCE uh so so that's uh that's the origin
of the of the Hebrew or or or Israeli or
Jewish culture and then they were taken
their nation was invaded by the what
Assyrians I believe and the Persians
helped them out and Jews were allowed to
live in Persia and eventually it was
King Cyrus King Krush who said allowed
the Jews to go and settle back in Israel
and then there was the I believe Solomon
King Solomon built a temple it was
destroyed and there was a second temple
which was then destroyed by the Romans
and then you had the Jewish diaspora
going around the world and you know
settling all across uh mostly in in
Europe some of them in Africa am there
was a time when even much of Arabia had
a significant Jewish presence uh Iran
also had a Jewish presence going back to
the time of king kurush or King Cyrus
and after the Roman destruction the the
Revolt of the mabes and the RO the Roman
occupation of Juda uh about 2,000
roughly years ago some some Jews even
came to India and so on so this is the
ancient history of Israel it's an
interesting topic I would encourage you
to you know read about it it's
interesting for sure and it uh you read
it you will understand the present day
situation kind of better always helps to
know
history all
right vom says can we test nuclear
weapons in space why not you want to see
a nuclear explosion in real time wake up
in the morning and look
eastwards but don't look at it directly
the sun the sun is a gigantic fusion
reaction nuclear fusion the fusion of
hydrogen atoms hydrogen nuclei together
together into helium and the light that
comes out of the sun each Photon of
light that comes out of the sun takes
between 100,000 to 1 million years to
emerge after it is born inside that's
how dense the sun is uh yeah so the sun
is a nuclear reaction it's it's a fusion
reaction caused by the implosion of of
this enormous mass of material mostly
hydrogen gas now so that we know all
these stars that we see in the night sky
Stars not planets but Stars those are
nuclear reactions now can we test
nuclear weapons in space well it's been
done uh what was it called I don't
remember the name of the test but there
was a test uh the Americans tested a
nuclear weapon in space uh I'm sure we
can we can yeah let's let's Google that
let's go to our friend
Google and uh yes they
have um yeah so what is it called
nuclear uh spelling nuclear test in
space so what was it called starfish
Prime there you go starfish Prime so
this is what it looks like so it cus
this Aurora like like phenomenon okay so
the Americans tested a nuclear weapon in
space uh there are various uh
photographs of that so it has been
done so the short answer to your
question is we can certainly test
nuclear weapons in space because the
nuclear uh pain reaction doesn't doesn't
depend on things like o the availability
of oxygen you know you can't burn a
flame in space because of the absence of
oxygen which a flame the fire is an
exothermic reaction it's a chemical
reaction and it needs
oxygen to happen without oxygen it won't
happen so you can't burn a flame in in
space in vacuum but you can
certainly ignite I mean set off a a a
chain reaction a nuclear Chain Reaction
a fishion reaction fusion reaction
whatever in space so yes you can
certainly test nuclear weapons in
space all
right uh let us see what
else um all right Jade says with the
ongoing deradicalization in the Middle
East solve the identity crisis in India
Pakistan Bangladesh and 56 OIC Nations
since all the roots lie in Saudi Qatar
Etc so I'm talking I'm sure you're
talking about the the Islamic religion
Muslim religion right
Islam uh yeah so we are seeing this
process of deradicalization in the
Middle East so if you look at historic
Arabia the nation that is now Saudi
Arabia it was historically the Arabian
Peninsula once again let us go to the
map to to see the place right let's do
that I'm sure we all know where the
Arabian Peninsula is but just in case
let's let's see so it's it's our
neighboring region just go west of India
cross the Sea of sashtra and you will
reach the Arabian Peninsula you reach
Oman you go further e so further west
you will reach Saudi Arabia so the
religion Islam it obviously emerged out
of this region from um Mecca Medina and
all that that so and historically if you
look if you go back 100 years 150 years
uh the kind of Islam the form of Islam
that was practiced in this region was
quite different from what was practiced
in the 20th century in the 20th century
you had a more AER more uh a more
fundamental I'm not sure more radical or
whatever you want to call it form of
Islam it's called wahhabism that was
invogue in the Arabian Peninsula it is
something that was encouraged by the
West the West needed to to maintain
control over this region because of the
oil Reserves at the time when I talk
about the West I mean the US and the UK
and eventually just the US the UK became
irrelevant 1956 onwards so it was the US
that this region force was essential for
the US see no
power okay no no geopolitical power can
survive without energy and the more
powerful you are the more energy you
need and this was this region was the
source of energy for the us and it
essentially owned this region right uh
it had complete control over this region
it still has actually to a very
significant extent and so they they
encouraged the local leaders the local
monarchies to impose a very strict and
very uh uh auster very radical form of
Islam on the region to keep people under
a great amount of very strict
control
and now that the US doesn't
need the gulf oil because it is now
self-sufficient in oil now it doesn't
care right so now we are seeing and now
we are seeing that the world is slowly
beginning to move away from from uh from
oil from uh petrochemical sources of
energy maybe toward something else so in
in the Arabian Peninsula the Nations
over here know that they cannot keep on
relying on their oil oil reserves and
oil exports forever they need to change
they need to start catching up with the
world they start need to start
attracting investment they need to start
attracting people to come into the
country and invest and and settle down
all that so to do that they need to open
up the economy they need to open up the
society as well so we are seeing that
process in action over there so we have
a very young Dynamic leaders like um
like uh Prince Muhammad bin Salman who
is doing that Saudi Arabia we have the
UA which is a wonderful place very
liberal very open we have a Hindu temple
that recently came up over there B's
Hindu Mand in Abu Dhabi and so on so we
are seeing significant changes happening
over here and yeah you could call it
deradicalization or whatever you
want so we think that oh there but will
it solve the identity Iden identity
crisis in India Pakistan Bangladesh Etc
I don't think so I think it could it
could trigger a a rather opposite kind
of reaction
in in India Pakistan Bangladesh and so
on probably possibly I'm not sure
because I'm not a great expert in in
Islamic
matters but yeah I think it could have
the opposite kind of effect outside of
the Arabian Peninsula let's see how it
goes we shall
see all right next
question
um K NAD says why is mathematics
considered the language of the universe
well to answer that question we have to
first ask ourselves what is
mathematics we know that 1 + 1 is two
and 1+ 1 is two here where I am over
here it is one 1+ 1 is two wherever you
are 1+ 1 is two on the moon it's one 1+
1 is two on Mars it's it's true
everywhere that we know of in the
universe right and similarly we have 2 +
2 is 4 and and so on so forth addition
subtraction multiplication division then
you have other branches of mathematics
you have calculus you have geometry all
of these things what do they represent
they represent
the they represent the regularities and
patterns of the universe so these are
Universal
facts and what we find is that using
mathematics you can formulate the laws
of nature
physics so that's that's why mathematics
hints to toward deeper truth so if you
were a programmer okay if you were a
programmer and you programmed the
universe then mathematics was the
language in which this programming was
done so if this universe is a simulation
that we live in and there's a programmer
out there beyond the universe who wrote
the code and did the programming and the
language of programming was
mathematics so yeah that's why to put it
very briefly that's why mathematics is
considered to be the language of the
universe the language of physics
physics if you want to do physics you
need to know math you can think
abstractly but to actually you know to
actually do physics to
calculate various properties of Nature
and all to solve problems you need
mathematics you cannot do Advanced
physics without knowing advanced
mathematics
unfortunately all right
um okay inand zero says do you think the
Israel Hamas conflict is a geopolitical
move by China or Russia or Iran or maybe
a combination to prevent the India
Middle
East uh Europe economic Corridor okay
let's let's consider this question so
yeah last year we had the G20 Summit yes
we in India had the G20 Summit in India
in New Delhi and in during the summit
during the summit meeting it was
announced that India was and and so this
this trade
Corridor economic and transport Corridor
was announced during the G20 Summit so
it is it is the intention is to connect
India
with Europe why the middle east region
why Oman Saudi Arabia Israel bypassing
turkey and going into Greece and further
into Europe and this would have
transportation this would have a supply
chains this would have trade and so on
and this uh Corridor has the blessings
of the United States and if it really
happens indeed then it'll be a major
Challenge and a significantly viable
alternative to the Chinese belt and Road
initiative the BR one belt one road one
belt to rule them all one road to bind
them so you know nations are pulling out
of the BR you know the the Pakistan uh
the Pakistan phase of B the CP isn't
working uh Italy has pulled out of the B
other nations are are beginning to see
that it's not going to be good for them
so the iMac India middle east Europe
trade Corridor was supposed to be a
great alternative to that now that this
entire
uh region is kind of extremely tense
there is there is uh you know there is
there are hostility is happening over
here there's a conflict happening
between Israel and Hamas which could
also involve hisbah which is in Southern
leanon and uh so because of this
conflict the India middle east Europe
trade Corridor is a non-starter for now
the Saudis wanted this to happen right
away they were saying that once the
thing is announced within 45 days we
should start creating building the
infrastructure they really really wanted
this to happen the Saudis but then this
thing this this conflict erupted out of
nowhere last year in the last quarter of
last year so the question is who
benefits from this obviously China
stands to benefit because the Challenger
to the
brri isn't taking off right now it's
kind of not happening yeah and we don't
know when this conflict will subside so
that we can start the project so yeah
that definitely benefits
China does it benefit Russia look if
China gets stronger economically and
geopolitically it's the Russians don't
see it as a good thing okay the major
threat see Russia has two major threats
one obviously is the United States the
other major threat just by looking at
the map it's clear that the major threat
for Russia is China this gigantic
country which is a very very major
economy the second largest economy in
the world and a significant military
power so yeah it's it's and the Russian
Far East you know the Russian Far East
the Far East part of Russia is almost
empty very very low population density
and when when we look at the
north east of China and the eastern part
of China it's its population is quite
dense large population over here so it's
it's a threat for
Russia and since the Americans have been
trying to isolate Russia and since they
have been trying to you know they've
essentially loaded all possible economic
sanctions on Russia there is a
significant threat a very real threat
that Russia could become overly
dependent on China and using my language
it could become a vasal of China and for
that reason Russia wants India to get
stronger Visa V China and India for
Russia is a pressure release wall when
it comes to all these sanctions and also
the Chinese threat and you should also
know that the Russians have ballistic
missiles pointed at China and the
Chinese have ballistic missiles pointed
at Russia so what we are seeing right
now is is is a temporary kind of
Alliance it it is it is temporary
cooperation and collaboration but both
Nations know that their major threat
right across the border is the Other
Nation so if the if the imch doesn't
take off and the Chinese brri gets a
Philip because of that it gets bolstered
then it's not a good thing for Russia so
I don't think Russia would have made a
move such as that or they would have
been you know induced by what
happened when it comes to
Iran um Iran has has its fingers in lots
of Pies in this region they are a nation
that has a significant appetite for
taking risks they are active beyond
their territory in Iraq which has a
significant Shia population they also
have ties with Syria they also have ties
with hisbah and Hamas they also have
interests in Yemen and so on and so
forth they have a strategic alliance
with China the Chinese are investing
roughly 400 billion dollars in Iran in a
strategic uh deal which is going to
happen over the next 25 or so years
there is Convergence between Iran and
Russia as well the Iranians have been
supplying Russia with uh with suicide
drones lering drones lering Munitions
that the Russians have been using in
Ukraine the Russians have been supplying
Iran with certain equipment including
fighter planes and and other stuff as
well so there is all of this going on
every nation has its own
interests every nation has interests
some Nations their interests converge
and align to a certain extent sometimes
more significantly sometimes less
significantly but every nation also
regards other nations as adversaries
also so it's like imagine a fish tank
imagine a fish tank every fish fish
wants to thrive some fish are big some
are small so some fishes make alliances
against bigger fish smaller fish like 20
small fish will get together against the
bigger fish some medium fish will get
together for their own purpose and they
will hunt the smaller fish and try to
save Safeguard themselves from the
bigger fish and so on so there is
constant Co cooperation as well as
competition in the world okay so I don't
think this conflict benefits Russia it
does benefit Iran it does benefit China
but definitely not Russia to that extent
that's how I see it it's complicated now
who really triggered this conflict who
set it off well I I think time will tell
I think time will
tell okay anur Singh says your views on
eight Indian ex Navy officers released
by
Qatar once again let's go to the map and
find out where is the nation of
Qatar so once again we go westwards from
India we cross the Sea of sashtra and we
have the Arabian Peninsula we cross Oman
we go westwards UAE and there we have
Qatar and bahin so this little Nation
Qatar is the nation that had uh held
eight Indian ex naal officers in prison
it had senten them to death for
allegedly indulging an Espionage on
behalf of third Nation okay and there
was a situation for quite some
time and what now what has now emerged
is that Kar has now released these eight
Indian ex Navy officers and as far as I
know they have all been at at least
seven of them have been repatriated I
hope by now the eighth person has also
been repatriated to India so it was a
significant
reversal you
see when when a foreign Nation takes
eight of your citizens puts them in
prison and sentences them to death I
think the best outcome you can hope for
is that the death sentence will be
revoked and there will be given a long
prison sentence that's typically the
best you can hope for but what's
happened here is that not only have the
death sentences been revoked they have
all been freed and theyve been
repatriated to India that is stupendous
that is a gigantic feat of diplomacy
it's a huge diplomatic win and then when
was it it was just a few days ago Prime
Minister Modi uh it was just uh like 10
days
ago uh Prime Minister Modi went visited
the the the Middle East he visited the
UAE for the inauguration of the baps
Hindu Mand where I was there I was there
in the inauguration and from there he he
went to Oman and he met the leadership
of Oman the the king or who the the the
Crown Prince or or ruler of Oman they
hugged and they had a very cordial meet
and he met all the all the principal
government officials and the and India
and Oman signed a very large deal for
the supply of LNG liquified natural gas
to India at a discounted rate so it's a
win-win situation Oman got this
gigantic deal with India India got a big
discount and India got its eight naval
officers back ex naal officers back I
mean talk about win-win diplomacy
everybody wins everybody goes back happy
and what the Indian government has done
is we have essentially converted a
potential enemy into a
friend I mean I'm sure you all know
there are no enemies and friends in
geopolitics but just using common
parlons common language we have
essentially converted a potential enemy
into a friend that I mean that is very
high level mature diplomacy very
effective diplomacy it's a it's a huge
Monumental win it essentially surprised
the entire world so my view is that this
is great it's a great outcome for India
it's a great outcome for Oman it's
win-win diplomacy everybody goes back
happy and everybody benefits from the
outcome I mean what else can you ask for
I think it's it's great great job by by
India push katar says why didn't why
India doesn't have any base in jibuti
well you could ask me why doesn't India
have a base in Greece or why does India
have a base in
Singapore I
mean India has military bases Beyond its
territory but you can't expect to have
bases everywhere
right and yeah I mean jibuti obviously I
mean let's once again go back to the map
jouti is an interesting place it's at
the it's at it occupies a vital choke
point the straight of bab al- mandb
between between this the Gulf of Aden
and the red the sea so here's this
little nation jibuti in Africa okay and
as you can see it it occupies a very
vital very strategic position
geographically at the mouth of the
straight of bab Al Mand you see bab al-
mandab straight where the last Out of
Africa migration probably happened from
you know humans crossed over from Africa
across the bab mandab straight and
eventually about 70 75,000 years ago
came into India and settled down here so
jibuti occupies this very important
place and there are two Nations that
have bases in jibuti one is the US the
other is China would you like to see the
bases I can show you the bases it's
interesting viewing so we have jibuti
the city of jibuti here okay now there
over here we have a International
Airport jouti
Uli and you have Camp lemon Uso and
let's take a look at the aircraft that
are parked here these are clearly US
military aircraft you have these large
Transportation aircraft you have these
uh you know these swing-wing
helicopters so you have a US presence
here you can see some more aircraft over
here these are all American aircraft US
aircraft well that's not all let me show
you something else there is a different
airst strip over here not sure you'll
see something interesting here but let's
try and see if there is something oh
yeah now check this out what does this
look like this is one of those drones
Reaper Predator whatever you want to
call it so once again you have a US base
here what else do we have well there is
this Chinese people's Liberation Army
support base so you have that here they
have their own little
thing and uh yeah this is a port it's
used by the Chinese so the Chinese and
the Americans are are uneasy easy bed
fellows in
jibou uh so that's the situation in
jibuti I hope it makes sense now uh now
for India to come here you would first
of all have to negotiate with the
government over here and the Americans
are already already unhappy about the
Chinese presence there they would
definitely not want an Indian presence
there so we have we we as in India we
have
certain bases beyond our territory I'll
talk about the ones that everyone knows
about so there is
the port of duum okay we have one here
uh is something visible hopefully not
would say so yeah we have we have some
some kind of presence apparently in duum
we also have certain presence in the
Indian Ocean region seel's some presence
uh in
macius we have some presence here as
well uh where is
it where is agala
okay I'll not go and look for it I'm
sure you guys can check it out and then
there is some presence um let's say in
Tajikistan as well okay so we we have
certain assets beyond our territory extr
territorial military bases that doesn't
mean that we are occupying those Nations
we are doing that with their consent all
right uh yeah so that's the deal with
India what is the region of interest for
us the region of our interest is the
Indian Ocean region
okay for that we need a friends let's
let's call it friends or or Partners in
this region one of the major partners
for India is France because France has a
significant presence in the Indian Ocean
region see this French Southern and ant
Antarctic Islands uh this again is is
French territory here
Alfred what is this here let me see Mar
research station South Africa this Maran
South Africa and then the French also
have reuno which is a French
territory and then they have a presence
in SEL and so on so the French are a
significant player in this region and it
makes sense for us to partner with them
so India and France have excellent
relations because it makes sense for
India and France to have excellent
relations and then we have a partnership
uh in the the Western Indian Ocean
region the quad essentially which is not
really a military Alliance but a quasi
military geopolitical kind of
partnership and then we we have good
relations with all the nations in the
eastern African region and we have good
relations with the gulf Nations the UA
Saudi Arabia Oman Etc and we also have
uh we have chabahar and I'm sure there
is some progress hopefully happening in
chabahar so overall we are trying to
secure our area of Interest the Indian
Ocean region jibuti well it's not that
important for us as of now and later we
will see see as we grow and get larger
and get more powerful we'll will I'm
sure we will rethink and revisit all of
this okay let us see other
questions I am not a trojan horse says
what's your opinion on Kerala I think
Kerala is a fantastic Place fantastic
Place great climate great people great
history what else what else can you ask
for I mean if you ask me for my for my
general opinion I'll say Cara is a
fantastic place the people of Kerala are
wonderful I love the climate in Kerala
love the weather love the love the
culture love the architecture love the
food what's not to love about this state
just like all other in the other Indian
States very interesting very unique and
uh place that people should
visit uh ad says when will polygamy ever
be banned in India as this would
interfere with the fundamental right to
freedom because Islamic text allowed to
marry four wives at once well look it's
a it's it's a question for the
government to decide I mean if you want
to look at uh if you want to look at
context and and precedence look at other
Islamic Nations look at Turkey for
example do they have polygamy there no
they don't is anyone complaining no
one's complaining uh look at extremely
Progressive Nations like the UK and the
US which have significant Muslim
populations do they have polygamy no
they don't have polygamy is anyone
complaining there no one's complaining
so I think it's it's just common sense
that that it should not be a problem uh
outlawing that practice in India but
overall I would say it's for the
government to decide it's not my
perspective that matters it's the
government's perspective and opinion
that matters and let them sort it
out uh let us see let us
see Lucario says what would be your
summary of the Tucker and Putin
interview a very interesting interview I
haven't seen the whole of it but uh uh I
am aware that Mr Putin first of all gave
a 30 minute plus history lesson about
the history of Russia and and the whole
region I remember just a couple of days
before the Ukraine war started in
February 22 I did an emergency podcast
with my friend ranir aladia we did it
did it uh we recorded like this not in
his place and he asked me about what the
deal is and I gave a 30 minute I don't
know 30 20 minute history lecture
because you have to go back into History
A Thousand Years or maybe more to
understand the context if there is a
problem today why does the problem exist
how was it created you have to go back
in history to understand that and what I
saw is that Tucker Carlson was getting
impatient he was trying to interrupt
Putin he was saying come to the point
and Putin said this is the point you
have to understand history the point one
of the most interesting things one can
see from this interaction is that the
Americans have no sense of history there
are how old is the us as a nation 200
years 300 years whatever it is 250 270
whatever 1700 something it was founded
right out of conquered
territory for them 200 years is ancient
history for India that's day before
yesterday for us a thousand years ago is
day before yesterday for the Russians
hist starts their history essentially
starts about 1200 years ago I would go
back 2,000 years well the first mention
of Slavic tribes but the Romans roughly
2,000 years ago but yeah Putin chose to
start about 11 1200 years ago it makes
sense and the in the westerners
especially the English speaking people
they don't understand that they have no
sense of History especially the
Americans the English British they do
have some sense of History their history
goes back
what Thousand Years 2,000 years they
don't identify with with with the PS and
the Kelts they identify with the Angles
and the Saxons the Angles and the Saxons
invaded the British Isles about 1600
years ago roughly 17 look it
up they defeated the the the Celtic
peoples and took over the place and then
the Normans invaded in the year
1066 William Duke William of Normandy
who was called William the bastard but
he conquered England the last Invader to
successfully conquer England and he then
was over forever known as William the
Conqueror so the British have some sense
of History the Americans don't and they
Tucker just could not wait for that
history lesson to get over so so it was
interesting to see how well Wladimir
Putin President Putin understands
history okay every national leader
should have a very good understanding of
history and a great historic sense a
very strong sense of of History because
everything that we experience today the
the way the world is it is the
consequence of it is it is the
consequence of things that happened in
the past and we have problems in the
world today and to understand how to
solve those problems you have to
understand how the problems were created
in the first place that's why history is
important to understand the cause and
effect chain that created the world as
it is today so to historic mistakes we
have to first understand how the
mistakes happened so Putin gave a very
very good overview of the past of the
overall of the overall history of the of
the Slavic people of the Russian people
the rose people he demonstrated that
Ukraine was nothing but the B lands of
Russia the West doesn't want to
acknowledge that that historical fact
but there it is and so on so uh I
haven't seen the entire interview it's
two hours seven or 8 Minute interview
but yeah that's what I can give view as
of now that these people have no
understanding or sense of History what
came across was that
Putin is intellectually in a league of
his own compared to most world leaders
there are very few who can come up to
that level he is extremely
intelligent and he can I mean taka
Carlson was was no match for
Putin right let's see other
questions
I agree Putin's 30 minute history lesson
was epic do I like do I like Star Wars
oh yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah I love Star
Wars one of my earliest memories as a
kid was going to a movie theater big
screen and watching Star Wars and I
thought at that time because I was like
what three years old four years old I
thought chewbecca was a
gorilla and I remember the lightsabers
and I remember Darth Vader so yes the
original Star Wars Trilogy was awesome
the first movie was great the second was
greater the third wasn't bad either and
then they created three more movies the
prequels which I haven't watched I've
seen the Revenge of the Sith which was
okay and then you have all these new
movies that have come out with God knows
what characters they've ruined the old
characters so the new movies I am not a
huge fan of I've seen one or two but uh
I can't remember anything about them
kylo Ren and what's that girl that girl
I forget that girl's name doesn't matter
not important so the first three movies
the original Three movies were awesome I
like those yeah big fan of movies
actually
okay please tell about dark Indian
education
system what's what's a dark education
system we have a very mediocre very very
poor education system in India today and
I have spoken at Great length about it I
have so if you go
okay let's let's uh since we have this
thing let's check it out uh let us go to
uh let's go and search on YouTube let's
search for
me and I'll show you what I mean by that
so this is my channel and uh if we go to
um live and you go back in time go back
go back go back go back then I have
three or four episodes only about
education around 29:30 ask abijit or
something let's see let's see where it
is okay so we have ask abijit 28 we have
ask abijit 30 and ask abijit 31 those
three are the education focused episodes
of ask ask abijit if you want to
understand what's wrong with the Indian
education system and what steps we need
to take to to improve it check out those
three episodes in detail I have gone
into all of that long time ago maybe two
years ago but yes if you want to
understand about India's dark education
system check out those three
episodes all right let
us how do I start watching Star Wars I
suppose it should be available on some
live on some OT platform I don't know
Netflix prime or Geo Cinema or or or
what hot star whatever it is I suppose
you'll be able to find it
somewhere Curren says if the sun has so
much gravity why doesn't the Earth fall
into it because the Sun the answer is
it's because the sun is not a vacuum
cleaner okay uh the universe follows
certain laws and the laws
state that well there is something
called orbits so if if if so if you
shoot a bullet into the sky okay from
the surface of the Earth it's going to
go up it's going to come down but if you
shoot the bullet with a certain amount
of velocity with a certain angle it will
go into all orbit around the Earth it'll
keep on trying to fall to the Earth but
never actually fall just keep on going
round and round and you have different
kinds of orbits you have elliptical
orbits you have polar orbits you have
all kinds of orbits Liu orbits I don't
go into that so there is something
called orbits and the earth and the
other planets are in orbit around the
sun I'm sure in the beginning of the
solar system when the whole uh Proto dis
formed lots of stuff would have fallen
into the sun after collisions and so on
but after everything settled down
after billions of years the solar system
is some 4 something billion years old so
now it's stable it has settled down over
a long time so now we have stable more
or less stable orbits of the different
planets eventually in the future maybe a
few billion years down the future you
may have more collisions between the
planets and some other stuff may happen
but as of today for all intents and
purposes we have a settled and stable
solar system so because of the laws of
nature
the Earth doesn't fall into the sun it
simply goes around the Sun in an
elliptical orbit as do all the other
planets and other material in the solar
system that we are aware of it all goes
around the Sun in
orbits so that's just physics orbital
mechanics you can check it out I mean
you can maybe search some YouTube videos
on orbital mechanics or find a textbook
so it's because of the laws of nature
that it's not falling into the into the
sun
um so this question I get all the time
how can India deal with the Pakistan
problem permanently and gain land access
to Afghanistan and Central Asia for that
to happen my dear friends the temporary
Nation would have to break up right and
that Nation Pakistan is Forever on the
brink of
collapse but it never collapses right so
why does it not collapse see there are
so so many forces within Pakistan that
that that don't get along together you
have so many
elements ethnic elements religious
elements linguistic elements other
elements that are pulling
Pakistan apart in different directions
and still there is one entity the
Pakistan Army and the isi that that
holds the nation together by force okay
the CIS would very much want
independence from Pakistan the boois
would very very much want independ from
Pakistan the pashun in
Kakak Province would very much want to
be reunited with their brein and sister
in in gandhar in Afghanistan and G Gil
balistan and P Etc would very much want
to reunify with their their Brethren
across the border in
India so all these
forces take Pakistan in different
directions but Pakistan is held together
by four Force by the isi and the
Pakistan Army and these are proxies of
much more powerful forces for the
longest time as we
know Pakistan bled India by doing
terrorism by exporting terrorism and
terrorists into India happened for
decades and all of these terrorist
activities were funded and financed by
the United States this is a
fact then for some time for a decade or
so Pakistan went into the Chinese
Embrace they became Iron brothers and
now Pakistan is back into the US Embrace
so as long as other more powerful
Nations have an interest in Pakistan
that Nation will exist it's a temporary
Nation but it will exist as long as it
serves a certain purpose what is the
purpose for which Pakistan was created
the purpose was to counterbalance India
to keep India off balance to keep on
bleeding
India that was a purpose and there are
other purposes as well to prevent well
the Great game from going forward in the
20th century and uh to serve certain
geopolitical interests of the West in
the Gulf region as well so all of that
so as long as this nation has value for
the West it's going to keep existing and
if the West loses interest then then the
Chinese may find Value in
Pakistan so to solve this problem
permanently India has to rise as a
power so if you if you go through my GE
politics course you will find that I I
calculate the actual power of each
Nation based on open- Source data open
source information numbers that are
available in public based on numbers you
can calculate the exact power score that
each nation has so the US has a score of
about 87 or something Russia has a score
of 50 Something China has a score of 15
or 16 India has a score of about 4 point
something then you have France then you
have other nations the top four nations
are the US which is a superpower then
you have Russia which is the near
superpower China which is a great power
and India and France are middle powers
and then you have other nations so for
India to be able to solve this problem
permanently India will have to transform
itself into a great power and you know
people believe that a nation's power
depends on its GDP ranking which is such
an asinine
thought okay GDP does contribute to the
score of a Nation power score but there
are lots of other factors that matter
GDP itself is nothing there are other
factors more important factors that you
have to take into consideration So based
on GDP us is number one Russia China is
number two Russia is nowhere India is
number five but based on actual power
scores the US is number one Russia is
number two China is number three India
is number four France is number five so
India's score is four China score is 15
or 16 us is 80 almost
90 so you can imagine the amount of
influence the US has as a global
superpower on this region so they are
able to make Pakistan survive for this
problem to be solved permanently India's
national power score needs to go into
the double digits should become
comparable to China then even then see
China still even though it has a power
score of of about 15 it's not able to
solve the Taiwan problem
which is in its own backyard so India
will to rise much higher then we can
solve the Pakistan problem it's about
Rising as a nation not just economically
but as a power as a global geopolitical
power hard power forget about soft power
soft power is nothing in geopolitics
it's only hard power that
matters there are components of hard
power there is economic strength there's
military strength there's nuclear
strength there's power projection there
is so much more that goes into the recip
for calculating a nation's power so
that's how India will eventually solve
this problem by Rising as a power is a
hard power economic military nuclear and
other things as well all of that has to
has to contribute to India's rise that's
how India can solve this temporary
problem
um aniket says how to remove inferiority
comp F from oneself that's a good
question you have to First Look it's
it's straightforward but not easy okay
first of all you have to start becoming
honest with yourself and you to
understand what are your you to First
understand yourself you to understand
your strengths and weaknesses everybody
has strengths and everybody has
weaknesses nobody is excluded from this
you to understand your strengths and
weaknesses you to understand what you
want to achieve in life okay how do you
know what you want to achieve in life
picture yourself on your deathbed last
day on the
planet and ask yourself what do you want
people to remember you
for what do you Tru truly want people to
remember you for that's all you have to
ask yourself that's your objective in
life now come back to today and ask
yourself where am I and where do I want
to reach the question is how do I get
there now some people may not be able to
figure out how to get there but the
thing is every problem has been solved
in the past there are only a small
number of problems in the
world okay but every time we try to
reinvent the wheel in solving these
problems so what you have to do is
understand how such problems were solved
in the past think of the people you
admire okay think of the people you
admire and ask yourself what has their
Jour Journey been like where did they
start from and where have they reached
and how did they reach there and try to
copy that
formula and try to raise your standards
the way to remove inferiority complex is
to raise your standards first identify
your strengths and weaknesses identify
what weaknesses you want to remove and
work on and understand it will not
happen tomorrow or next week it it will
be a long process give yourself five
years but start working towards it and
maybe you can create a dashboard a score
of whatever and when you start seeing
progress you feel better about yourself
you start feeling better and you keep on
working towards it consistently
discipline hard work it's not easy but
by doing that you will start feeling
better about yourself you'll start
feeling
confident and that's how you typically
do it there's no
shortcut and it's simple but very hard
but you got to do it you have to do it
you have to keep raising your
standards the way to remove any
inferiority complex is to raise your
standards and work very very hard hard
every day when you go to bed you should
know that I work worked as hard as I
could but not harder than that and and
also work smart work hard work smart so
that's how you do it by raising your
standards and knowing that you are
raising your standards
okay uh Vin wants long hair and
hairstyle like me well do it I mean it's
a passive thing just grow your hair stop
stop getting a haircut and give give
yourself what a year year and a half
you'll have long hair that's it and
tight behind you that's it done easy
easy
peasy all
right uh sidhart Singh Raj says what
really happened in the Battle of halati
according to you and shed some light on
the history and significance of
Rajasthan well there are two questions
let's take one question question let's
talk about the Battle of alati so this
was a battle between who was it Maharana
Pratap and the forces of the Tyrant
Akbar Jalal Akbar okay and sadly
unfortunately what by the time by the
time Akbar was in power he had captured
a significant portion of India
significant part of India and turned
various local Kings into his
wasal and when you are a
wasal you have to do what is what your
what you what your over tells you so
what happened was that the forces of
this Tyrant Akbar were led by rajputs
who was it Man Singh was it or somebody
so you had a battle between two rajput
forces but one rajput force represented
the Tyrant The Turk Akbar and the other
was maratab so what were the objectives
of the two sides what was akbar's
objective jalaludin akbar's objective
what was Maharana PR's objective the
objective of jalaludin Akbar was to
defeat Pratap and either kill him and
take his kingdom or defeat him and turn
him into a
wasal these are the objectives of the
tur
forces the objective of the rajput
forces Mahar pratap's forces the
objective of Maharana Pratap was to
remain
independent not die and not become AAL
independent two different objectives one
side wants to remain independent the
other side wants to either destroy the
enemy or turn him into a Wasa two very
different objectives now what happened
there was a battle lasted a few hours
lasted a day or whatever at the end of
the battle what were the object what was
the
outcome at the end of the battle
Maharana pratab was still alive and he
was still not a vasal of the
Turks so who achieved their objectives
did the Turks did did jalaludin akbar's
forces achieve their objective of
killing Marana Pratap or turning him
into aasal they failed to achieve that
objective Marana Pratap achieved his
objective of staying alive and staying
independent so there you go that's how
it is you to understand the outcome of a
battle or a war you have to first
analyze what are each side's
objectives and then see what was the
outcome and who achieved their
objectives it's as simple as that so
from this very logical analysis it's
clear that the forces of Akbar failed to
achieve their objective and the forces
of Marana Pratap achieved their
objective that's how I see it you may
feel you may you are free to agree or
disagree that's not an
issue uh did you watch Society of the
snow I have not watched it it's about
the plain plane crash in the Andes
Mountains right uh let's go to the maps
map uh where are the Andes if in case
you are
wondering it's a mountain
range it's a mountain range in South
America so let's go to South America and
you have a mountain range in South
America called the Andes and it actually
extends northwards and it becomes the
rocky mountain range in North America so
okay so I'm not sure it's if it's
visible from here but uh was it Chile
was it Peru I don't remember which part
of South America it was but what
happened is that there was a football
team okay a football team which was
traveling in an airplane and this
airplane crashes in the Andes Mountains
high up on the mountains where it's all
Frozen and
snowy okay and uh The Rescuers aren't
able to look locate the crash today we
have GPS and stuff we still lose ples of
course but yeah uh The Rescuers the
rescue operations were unable to locate
the location of the crash and these
people some of them survived a large
number of them survived some died but
they were stranded on on the uh Andes
mountain range in extremely cold
conditions snowy conditions and there
was no rescue for I don't know months I
suppose so they were left with a very
horrible Choice how do we survive there
was no food source available water was
there you can melt snow and drink it or
you can just eat snow which is not
advisable but yes there there was
plentyful water from the snow but there
was no
food they were left with a very horrible
Choice what do we do to survive and they
resorted to cannibalizing the dead
bodies and that's how they survived and
eventually they were located after a
long long time and there is a memorial
up there where the crash happened and so
on
and and I have not seen this movie
Society of the snow but I've seen a
movie that came out about 20 30 years
ago which was a good movie pretty
harrowing so I've seen that I don't
remember the name of the movie but yes
I've seen an older movie not the not the
new
one
uh Anisha says will MBA be relevant in
the next 5 years as more and more it
professionals are losing their job and
they going for MBA so that's a good
question what is MBA master in Business
Administration so you essentially become
an administr you gain the skills
apparently that enable you to be an
administrator of business or a manager
of kinds of some of some kind you
understand what a business is and what
are the different components of business
and how to manage it efficiently and
administ it efficiently and so on so
people with MBS typically get those
middle management positions and
eventually they can even write R to you
know c s level C Level uh ranks you know
CEO C CFO coo
Etc uh so that's what an MBA apparently
gives you and there are some very good
institutes in India like the iims ETC
the one in amdavad is supposed to be the
best is if I'm not mistaken uh now
Anisha is saying that more and more it
professionals are losing their jobs and
they're going for
MBA so listen in any business in any
industry you need a certain number of
managers but if you have seven times
that number in the market looking for
jobs they will not there will there will
not be enough jobs for
them so yeah MBA is is something that's
attractive you get a good salary I
suppose and you get good job positions
and all but if there are too many mbas
in the market then there's going to be a
surfe a surplus of mbas and then many of
them will be jobless the question is why
are these it professionals losing their
jobs I suppose this is one of the
reasons is the uh is the emergence of
artificial intelligence
Ai and lots of coding jobs are going to
AI today people with no coding knowledge
or experience can ask whatever AI tool
they use to generate code for them and
explain the code and and make it run as
well so yeah AI is going to bring a
shift in the market lots of skills are
going to get obsolete obviously it
doesn't make all coding all programming
obsolete you will still need good
programmers but maybe less good
programmers uh and and it's going to put
lots of people out of out of business
out of and people have to re will will
have to resk skill themselves and the
solution is not to go and get an MBA the
solution is to go and get skills that
cannot be
replaced so um I don't know see
eventually these degrees
will they will not be worth a
lot the way I see it I mean if you look
at the education system overall we have
all the in the take the Indian education
system as an example if you want to get
a good job you need to have a master's
degree and typically it doesn't matter
what master's degree you have you can
have a master's degree in English
literature and as long as you have a
master's degree you would be eligible to
apply for a certain kind of
job and then the question is what skills
did you gain from that master's degree
or bachelor's degree or whatever it is
these degrees they simply waste your
time most of them and they don't give
the skills you need to start performing
in a certain job or industry typically
what happens is for example if you want
to go into it you come with some degree
and then your company whichever company
hires you is if you're a fresher they're
going to have to train you from scratch
train you from scratch they're going to
have to teach you how to start a
computer these days you don't know need
those skills but how to do Hello World
programming and go on from there ideally
you want to have students who come out
with those skills ready to you know hit
the ground
running uh So eventually I think only
skills will matter not degrees and your
resume is going to be your portfolio
what stuff have you already created
during your time as a student for
example if you into websites how many
websites did you Cote or design or
create towards the websites if you are
some into something else what other code
did you create or what what what things
did you deploy and so on so forth so
that your your portfolio is going to be
a resume so for example if I were hiring
okay I would not care what degree you
have I would only care what skills you
have and your skills have to be
demonstrable I would ask you to show me
what what what you have created over the
past I don't know year two years
during your your internship as a student
or whatever it is I would like to see
what you are capable of creating and
contributing I don't care what degree
you have and event in the US there are
lots of companies that no longer care
about degrees they only do extensive
interviews and they see actually what
skills you have I think eventually India
always lags behind in these things when
the US does something five or 10 years
later India starts doing the thing so I
think it's going to happen eventually in
India as well people will not care about
your degree they will just care about
your
skills um So eventually degrees will
become irrelevant and Obsolete and maybe
you will have different kinds of
different kind of education you know
nowadays we moving towards open textbook
exams and all that which is a good move
I I would say because it doesn't you
know whatever you can refer to
immediately doesn't matter so I think
eventually all degrees will become more
or less irrelevant and obsolete not just
the MBA but other stuff but maybe there
are certain things that are taught in
mbas that actually are skills that are
worth having so maybe if you do an MBA
from a really good institution it may be
still relevant but
hopefully yeah all
right she bab CCP W asks who were the
Huns what was their origin so the Huns
well the name the Huns comes from
ancient India we used to call those
people they were Invaders we used to
call them scha
hunas and they attempted to invade India
during the reign of the Gupta Empire the
Gupta dynasty the Gupta dynasty emerged
out of magad their original cap capital
was partly
Putra and from there they moved to I
believe uh where was it
ojan I I can't recall but you can look
it up so during the rain of the Gupta
Empire the Gupta dynasty which was a
golden age for India the whole of India
more or less was once again politically
unified at that time these these
Marauders this these uh nomadic
Invaders Unleashed wave upon wave upon
wave of invasion on India and our
emperor scanda
Gupta he repelled wave after wave after
wave of hnik
invasion he he swore an oath that I will
not eat in a PL from a plate and I will
not sleep in a bed until I defeat the
Invaders and throw them out of my
country I will eat food from from a leaf
and I will sleep on the floor until I
achieve this and he achieved that great
guy skandagupta
great defender of
India so these Huns what was their
origin their origin was more or less
where we have Mongolia today in this
region in Mongolia inner Mongolia and
the Chinese called these Nomads they
called them the Shu s i o n g nuu or
something like that okay so they emerged
from this region the Huns and the
Mongols essentially had similar Origins
maybe they were the same uh ethnic stock
and the Huns then spread westwards they
expanded
westwards the westward expansion of the
Huns it uh
it
dislodged the kushans from from this the
eastern part of Central Asia and the
kushans started fleeing
westwards and because of the westward
fleeing of the kushans the skians
started fleeing southwards and they
invaded India as a
consequence so you had the skan invasion
of India the
skians simulated into Indian Society
very harmoniously today we don't know
who has keian ancestry who has not and
doesn't doesn't matter but Northern
Western India India you have people with
a significant amount of indos skan
ancestry and the skians themselves were
of Indian origin by the way so that's a
whole different story The kushans too
then the kushans invaded India and you
had the kushan empire keska was one of
our greatest Kings who did more than
most Kings could ever do in their
lifetime for Indian culture and the
Indian national interest keshka and then
during the Gupta Ira you had the hunnik
invasions of India and the Huns tried
the tried invade India at the same time
that they were invading the Roman Empire
so you can see how widespread they were
the Huns
okay so uh they were defeated repeatedly
by scanda Gupta but after the downfall
of the Gupta era of the of the Gupta
dynasty the Huns did make significant
inroads into India they first conquered
Gandhara the Gandhara region the
northwest of India
um I believe one of their kings one of
the honik Kings built the Buddhas in
bamyan okay most likely and then you had
Kings like uh what was his name miir Kul
who was hated by all because he was an
adharmic person he persecuted the the
brahans he persecuted the Buddhist he
persecuted everybody so mul was was a
very adharmic King nobody liked him
everybody remembered him with bitterness
but then there were good honik Kings as
well so they established the Kabul
Hindu Shahi Dynasty in Gandhara and they
defeated they defended India from the
Turks for a significant amount of time
and then you had other honik kings who
settled down in various parts of India
including all the way in Rajasthan and
Northern Gujarat as well and so on so
there were so to once again make a long
story short the Huns were Nomads they
were uh they they spread across the
whole of Eurasia they tried invading
India at the same time that they were
trying to invade the Roman Empire they
were defeated by the Gupta emperor in
India scand Gupta but they defeated
Rome okay they had significant success
in invading Rome and they eventually
made inroads into India and they also
settled down in India and assimilated
into Indian society and once again today
if you go to Northern India you will
have people with some hnik ancestry and
they won't even know about it and they
won't care because it doesn't matter so
yeah that's about the Huns
Thea
hunas
um okay compact 786 says How likely is
it for NATO Nations to invade the
Republic of Iran in order to disturb the
trade routes for
Russia interesting hypothetical question
let's take a look at the map so we're
talking about an invasion of Iran Persia
so as you can see Iran is located west
of India I mean you know you know what I
mean okay so the question is how does
one how does a major power let's say
nato invade a nation like Iran so for
example let's talk about their previous
Invasion or in the region which was the
invasion of Iraq so NATO which is
essentially the US it completely changed
the balance of power in the Middle East
region in West Asia in first in 1991 to
a certain extent and then in 2003 to a
complete extent by in 2003 they invaded
Iraq and
destroyed the government of Iraq and
they destroyed the nation as well and
then they imposed a puppet government
there which kind of still continues the
Iraqi government today has been
requesting the Americans to please leave
the country but they refus to
leave okay so how did they invade Iraq
first of all in 91 how did the Americans
invade Iraq they assembled a
significantly large very large
multinational Force Coalition in
invasive invasive Coalition of Nations
which was mostly led by them only and
the invasion was launched from various
nations from the Persian Gulf from Saudi
Arabia and so on so forth and they
started with a very heavy aerial
bombardment of the nation which kind of
killed God knows how many people and
weakened the the reime of Saddam Hussein
and then they
left
then they returned in 2003 and they
finished the job George W bush finished
the job that his father had
started so to do this so now to invade
Iran it's a whole different story first
of all in Iran has strong allies in
Russia and in China and Russia is not
really that far
away Russia is Right north of Iran if
you cross the Caspian Sea and and
Nations like turkistan kazakistan Etc
are you could say Nations that are very
much Russian proxies or wasal to a
significant extent none of these nations
can go against Russia they are in the
Russian zone of influence sphere of
influence so Russia has access to Iran
VI the Caspian SE and also VI these
nations kazakistan turkistan Etc even a
nation like
azaran could be used by Russia to uh
support
Iran possibly that's a possibility now
to invade Iran the Americans or NATO
let's say nato would need to do it VI
the Gulf of Oman or the Persian Gulf
which is very difficult or from the
Saudi Peninsula which would open up
Saudi Arabia or the Gulf Nations to
Iranian
retaliation Now understand this the NATO
countries Now understand this forget the
map for now the NATO
Nations have been supplying Ukraine with
arms and
ammunition in the proxy war against
Russia which was started by the Russians
in February
2022 so I'll not go into the history of
the Ukraine war but the Americans and
the NATO Nations have been supplying an
endless stream of arms and ammunition to
Ukraine what that tells you is that the
amount of arms and ammunition that are
available with NATO are at possibly an
alltime low especially
ammunition
bullets artillery shells missiles
Rockets whatever else they have been
supplying this to Ukraine so they are
running low on all these things okay
Iran has been a nation at peace for a
very long time they have been hit by
tremendous amount of sanctions by the
Americans sure but they have not been at
war with anyone for a long time and and
they have a good defense industry and
they have good supplies from Russia
Russia is open to giving them supplies
so the Iranians have significant
ballistic missile capabilities they are
very good at producing
drones and all the and all the US bases
military bases Etc in the uh Gulf region
in the Middle East region are very much
Within range of Iranian missiles
ballistic missiles cruise missiles
drones whatever the Iranians are able to
supply Yemen the huis the ansar Allah
faction in Yemen with drones and other
ammunition and other weapons which is uh
enabling them to kind of blockade the
straight of bab al- mandb because of
which all the global Supply chains are
now having to pass through the south of
Africa the Cape of Good Hope you know
there's priy also happening from Somalia
at the same time time so Iran is able
to supply Yemen the Anar faction in
Yemen with arms and ammunition they have
their hands in Iraq as well they're able
to have a good alliance an effective
alliance with Hamas andah as well so
they are a nation that
is has a significant appetite for taking
risks they have a very good defense
industry they have a tremendous amount
I'm sure of arms and ammunition it's not
going to be easy
to invade Iran if if if NATO tries to
invade Iran they may end up losing
possibly many of their bases in the
Middle East
region it's not going to be easy and
especially if Russia gets involved so
when the Americans tried to take out
Syria Syria almost fell I mean the Isis
or whatever forces were on the on the
outskirts of Damascus damask and then
the Russians stepped in and saved Syria
so the Russians could do the same in
Iran I'm
sure so it's not going to be easy it's
not going to be like Iraq like the
invasion of Iraq it's going to be a
whole different ball game if NATO wants
to invade Iran and if it doesn't go the
way they want it to go then it will be a
huge huge blow to their
credibility so I don't think it's a risk
they want to take right now I don't
think the Americans are open to taking a
such a risk at this point in time
so yeah it's not going to be easy if
they do want to do
that all
right gang matur says is India going
towards dictatorship I mean
what who's telling you that India is
going towards dictatorship we have an
election coming up in in a couple of
months national election we have
elections every every few months in
across the various states of India India
is a very active democracy it's a very
chaotic democracy we have hundreds of
political parties in India where is the
dictatorship if people vote for a
certain
leader and keep voting for The Leader it
doesn't mean that India has become a
dictatorship what do you mean by
dictatorship what's the the definition
of dictatorship a dictatorship is a
nation in which you have a single
political
party and and that party decides who
will rule you that's a dictatorship
China north Korea and in certain Nations
you have two political
parties two political parties not one
two it is one step above North Korea and
China a nation like the
US and doesn't matter who comes to power
they have the same foreign policy that's
a dictatorship in India if a new party
comes to power the foreign policy will
take a 180 degree turn that's not a
dictatorship this is a
democracy now let's say let's say
hypothetically India is going towards a
dictatorship is that such a bad
thing think back to the times in India's
history when India was very prosperous
and very
powerful the morian
Empire the G the the the kushan Empire
the Gupta Empire the cha Empire the
marata
Empire that's when India was at it at
its peak was the were those democracy
those were monarchies those were
dictatorships but that's when India did
the best
historically was was Lord Krishna a
Democrat or a
dictator he was king of dwarka did he
become king of dwarka through an
election was Lord
Rama elected by the
people so my point is what really
matters for a nation is long-term
security and prosperity
self-determination good living standards
and a long-term good future for your
descendants that's what matters the type
of political system doesn't really
matter actually it doesn't matter
whether the cat is black or white as
long as it catches mice you want good
outcomes it doesn't matter how you
achieve those good outcomes dictatorship
democracy whatever and India is not
going towards dictatorship dictatorship
I don't know where these ideas come from
really but yeah it's good to see
that all
right
um let's see some other
questions
um cost says was Hamas aware that Israel
is a nuclear State and can use nukes if
needed everyone knows Israel is a
nuclear
State um it's well known that Israel has
a nuclear weapons program that was
disclosed that was that was that was
leaked in the 1970s or
80s by a guy called morai vanunu so
morai vanuno was
a you want to see
something I can show you something so
let us go to
Israel okay let's open this satellite
image this is Israel and uh let us go
towards
biva and there is a place called
diona yes
diona now near
diona not in the city of De diona but
somewhere nearby there is this
uh is this the
one let me see no this is
a fertilizer plant is it well there's
got to be something else
tuna is it
here
uh beer
Shiva sure it's somewhere here ah here
we have it the ngv nuclear Research
Center and you can see this Doo here the
coolant Dome of a nuclear reactor so
this individual this guy morai vanunu
was the technician over here and he
surreptitiously took images of what was
happening inside and then he leaked it
to I believe a British publication
called news of the world or something
like that and that's how the world came
to know that the Israelis had nuclear
capabilities and they had nuclear
weapons so I think it's a welln fact
that Israel is a nuclear weapons Power
It is believed to have something like 80
to 100 nuclear warheads which it can use
so the whole world knows this it's not
something new Hamas obviously knows that
Israel is a nuclear weapon
state it doesn't
matter when you know nuclear weapons
come into play when you
have two Powers fighting each other and
one power is in the bring of of of
collapse or or or going out of existence
that's what nuclear weapons come into
come into play into Force you cross when
you have a nuclear weapons power a
nation and you cross certain red lines
for them that's when they can retaliate
with nuclear weapons but you can't use
nuclear weapons against
terrorists think about it logically let
me give you a different example in our
own
neighborhood we have a temporary Nation
Pakistan we have
Afghanistan Pakistan we know is a
nuclear weapons power it has a number of
nuclear weapons the
Afghans have no nuclear weapons but the
entire Afghanistan Pakistan border is
active there are military clashes
happening every day the pashon
nationalists that are the Taliban they
do not recognize the Pakistan
Afghanistan border the Duran line and
they want large parts of Pakistan back
in Afghanistan so the the pakistanis
have a huge border dispute with
Afghanistan and there are daily military
clashes the pakistanis have even done
air strikes in
Afghanistan but there's no point
threatening the Taliban with nuclear
weapons the Taliban are not a nuclear
weapons power Afghanistan is sparsely
populated and it's a war crime to use
nuclear weapons against civilians you
understand so even though Pakistan is a
nuclear weapons power that those nuclear
weapons are pointless when it comes to
combating Afghanistan they may come on
to play with Iran okay Iran these days
has been quite active Visa Pakistan
surgical strikes latest news we heard so
similarly when it comes to Israel the
state of Israel against a terrorist
outfit like Hamas there's no point
talking about nuclear weapons you have
to deal with them in a different way
this is asymmetric Warfare that we're
talking about so uh Israel is in no
position to use nukes against
Hamas the entire world would turn
against Israel if it does that why does
Israel have nukes it has nukes as a last
resort the Samson option Israel is in a
very bad neighborhood it has you know
its neighbors have gone to war with it
multiple
times so the purpose of the Israeli
nuclear weapons is that if all the
neighbors of Israel come together and
invade Israel and Israel is on the
brink of being destroyed then Israel
will destroy all its neighbors before it
is destroyed that is the Samson option
that's why Israel has nuclear weapons
they're not they have not been developed
to use them against
terrorists
okay red chile says mea question kab
loai okay what's your question sir I see
you have to make your question visible I
took this but you there is no question
here so yeah ask a question maybe I'll
notice it there are see there are
hundreds of questions coming every few
minutes
so please be
patient all right let's see something
else
uh let us
see some other
questions uh okay let's see this Yash
Kapoor says please tell us how we can
solve the issue of illegal immigrants
coming to India not from not only from
Bangladesh but also Nepal and other
neighbor nebor in countries look Nepal
is not an
issue if if people come into India from
Nepal first of all the Nepal citizens
have the right to coming into India
that's not illegal immigration every
Nepali citizen has the right to come to
India live in India work in India do
whatever they want the only thing is
that they cannot vote in India they can
serve in the AR Indian Armed Forces we
are we have an open border with Nepal
there is no issue with nepales citizens
no issue at all so I welcome nepales to
come to India if they want to the issue
is not Nepal the issue is Nations like
Bangladesh and increasingly Myanmar
Burma now Burma is a friendly Nation
actually they are the same culture as
us but the problem is the the certain
parts of Burma are are not no longer
under government control and the tribal
groups that live in northern and western
Burma are not even
Burmese they don't speak the Burmese
language they don't practice burmes
culture they don't respect burmes
culture or the burmes language or the
nation of
Burma one well the group that we are
talking about obviously is the cookies
the so-called cookies they are fighting
against India they're fighting against
Burma they're fighting against
Bangladesh three
nations and they have been pouring into
Manipur in lacks and they've completely
changed the demographics of Manipur
completely totally and this situation
was created by the post Independence
governments of India who kept the Border
open okay and who allowed these people
to come in just keep coming in keep
coming in and then the Modi government
inherits This
Disaster so it's a situation that has
happened over a century roughly is going
to take time so the first thing we have
to do is to start fening the border and
it's it's easier said than done take a
look at this border it's all Hill
and mountains and forests it's going to
take years and years and years to to
fence this border and then there is the
issue of mizoram which I will not go
into okay I'll not go into the issue of
mizoram which is an even bigger headache
for India so this entire border will
have to be Fen can you see the size of
the Border how big it is it's completely
open okay this should have been
fenced in the
1950s so now there are all kinds of
issues with that and then we have the
issue of with Bangladesh now tell me we
have a proper fencing done with
Bangladesh and still there are all not
everywhere but to a large extent but
still there are Bangladesh is who keep
pouring into India now why is this
happening clearly there is corruption at
various levels in C in certain States
perhaps in certain border security
agencies perhaps I'm just saying perhaps
okay so these things will have to be
tackled by the government of India there
are deep rooted problems that have been
around for
decades these problems have been around
for decades and it will take some time
to solve them so we have to fence all
the borders and we have to place the
right kind of Border Personnel on the
borders not the kind of personnel who
will take a a th000 rupee bribe from a
Bangladeshi and take all lot the
Bangladeshi into
India I'm just
saying so these things take time these
are not easy solutions you can't just
flip switch and make everything right
takes time so these problems have been
created by the past governments of India
useless I don't have words to to express
my
frustration how lightly they have taken
National Security they've played with
National Security and the Integrity ter
Territorial and demographic Integrity of
India so yeah this is a huge problem we
we acknowledge the problem exists and
we're going to have to solve it one way
or the other
all
right uh let us see some other
questions uh shubam pawar says what do
you think of India's cut in un funds
will it make any pressure on un
countries or five permanent Security
Council Members give a view give us a
view of India and five permanent
security members so there is something
called the UN Security Council which has
five permanent members and a whole bunch
of other nations that are voted in and
out okay I'll not go into the process of
how it happens but there are five
permanent members of the UN Security
Council who are these
members the US the UK
France China and Russia so it used to be
the USSR now it's Russia they wanted
their India to be there but Mr Neu kept
refusing so then they brought China in
okay and then you have France and the UK
so
this constitution of the UN Security
Council represents the winning Alliance
of 1945 at the end of the second world
world war the winning Alliance was
essentially these nations China was not
there it came in later but it was still
on the side of the Americans at that
time at that point in time so the
composition of the UN Security Council
which is a veto wielding body each
member has a veto the composition
reflects the reality of 1945 and the
global geopolitical situation of 1945
today we are in
2024 this happened almost a 100 years
ago almost a century ago it does not by
any means represent today's ground
realities and yet these VTO wielding
members of the UN Security Council are
entrenched in there they holding on to
this little power that they have it
gives them not a little power but a
great amount of power and a great amount
of
influence now today the world's most
populous nation one one of the most
powerful nations in the world is not a
member of the UN Security Council so
doesn't make any sense so
clearly something has to be done and it
you know the security Council will not
reform itself
it won't happen by on its own you're
going to have to pressurize
it the main thing
is from India's perspective India needs
to become more powerful India needs to
keep on working on its economic growth
its overall growth in terms of power and
there will come a time when India will
be so large so economically powerful and
militarily Powerful overall powerful
that the UN Security Council membership
will become become
irrelevant because power has a language
of its own power exerts pressure
pressure externally so once you are at a
certain stage at a certain
level then whether you are a member or
not of the UN Security Council becomes
irrelevant because you can anyway get
your way make your way in the world the
way you want it so but as of now India
is not that powerful India is slightly
above France in terms of geopolitical
hard power
and much below
China okay so as of today all India can
do is is India can play the long game
how does India play the long game you
keep on repeating in global forums that
the UN Security Council needs to be
reformed you keep on saying it over and
over and over again and the more you
grow and the more you matter the more
people will have to be forced to hear
you and eventually it will have some
effect maybe 20 years down the line so
India is playing the long
game but right now what India has done
is India has so every nation every
member of the UN typically contributes
some funds to the UN some Nations
contribute more funds some Nations
contribute uh soldiers to the UN
peacekeeping forces and so on and so
forth and India has been one of the
major contributors to the UN
peacekeeping forces in terms of soldiers
Manpower and India is also one of the
major funders of the UN so we have
now uh cut the funding
substantially because what's the point
in keeping on funding this organization
that is kind of you know to a certain
extent corrupt and to a certain extent
it doesn't reflect today's realities and
it it just exists as a as a tool of
other more powerful nations in the hands
of other more powerful Nations it
doesn't serve the global interest it is
not a fair and impartial organization so
because of this reasons it doesn't make
sense for India to keep funding it to
that extent that's why we've cut the
funding and we are keeping on applying
the
pressure and keeping on saying that the
UN Security Council needs to be reformed
the UN as an organization as an
institution itself needs to be
fundamentally reformed that's what we
are doing and that is a rightous and
just
cause
okay
Chan says how might the global landscape
change if nuclear weapons were rendered
obsolete it would totally transform the
global
landscape it would make
Russia lose a significant amount of its
geopolitical power you see today
Russia's economy isn't doing great it's
I think it's not even in the top 10 from
the GDP perspective Russia is an
autarchy an autarchy what's an autarchy
an autarchy is a nation it's it's a
nation that is self-sufficient in all
fundamental aspects in terms of energy
coal gas oil all of that in terms of
food production agricultural production
in terms of fertilizer in terms of raw
materials everything that you can think
of Russia is completely self-sufficient
so Russia is the only nation large
nation in the world that is a genuine
autarchy so that is a plus point from
Russia's perspective a significant plus
point but from a global hard power
perspective much of its hard power comes
from its enormous nuclear weapons
Arsenal Russia has the world's largest
arsenal of nuclear warheads nuclear
weapons and Delivery Systems so a
significant amount of its hard power
comes from that if those disappear
Russia will be open to all kinds of
attack the one thing that's holding the
us back and possibly also China is the
danger that Russia's nuclear weapons
pose nobody wants to cross that line
when it comes to Russia Russia is that
capable it can annihilate anyone I mean
it doesn't want to but it's there so if
nuclear weapons were rendered obsolete
it would take away significant portion
of Russia's power significant portion of
America's power as well it would
completely transform the global
geopolitical power landscape completely
transform transform it and then other
things would come to the four things
like your your conventional power your
economic power your energy
self-sufficiency your uh power
projection and so many other things
those things would become
more uh more important so yeah if you
were to make these weapons obsolete it
would totally
transform the global geopolitical
landscape
okay
um geopolitics is a blood sport with no
friends and just temporary alliances dog
ATS dog with no mercy and complete
ruthless tactics to achieve goals
geopolitics is murder and killing well
you can have rules you know we live in
the so-called rules-based World Order
which means that the rules and the order
are made by the most powerful Nation the
US and everybody else just plays along
and the Americans can change the rules
anytime they want and they keep on doing
that but as long as you play by their
rules they will solve you and let you
survive so it's not about completely
about murder and killing there is a
certain amount of that I mean whenever
the Americans invad a nation it's not
pretty they essentially flatten entire
nations U so yeah no friends I agree and
there are temporary alliances certain
certain alliances are more long lasting
when two Nations don't have a common
border are significantly apart
geographically and they have a
significant convergence of interests
then those those alliances can be very
long-lasting
alliances so some alliances are more
transactional some alliances are more
temporary some alliances are very long
lasting some alliances are almost
friendly especially when the cultures
are similar then you can have actual
friendship you know when when there is
People to People warmth then can there
can actually be friendship on a People
to People level and when there is
cultural alignment there is a more
closer kind of relationship but yes at
the end of the day it's about
self-interest first uh sometimes it can
be a Blood Sport as we have seen so many
times in history so overall I I agree
with this overall I agree
yeah
okay shras Sunil says why does the IMF
keep bailing out Pakistan given its
track record what is the real purpose of
IMF the real purpose of the IMF F and
the World Bank and all these Global
bodies is to do the bidding of their
Master these are not
impartial benevolent
organizations what world are you living
in Dear
Sir do you think the World Bank and the
international mon monetary fund exist to
help out the poor and disadvantaged
people of the world and to help out poor
Nations these
organizations exist to serve their
Masters these organizations were
created by certain
powers these organizations first of all
where is the IMF located let's let's try
and Google this IMF headquarters shall
we let's let's try and Google IMF
headquarters where is it
located
IMF
headquarters it is Washington DC United
States oh my God what a big surprise
what about World Bank let's see World
Bank World Bank headquarters oh
Washington DC United States oh my God oh
my God what about the United
Nations
Headquarters Midtown Manhattan New York
City us do you get the
point do you get the
point see the world that we see is a
world of Maya it's a make believe world
you if you if you watch you know a TV
news reader they're going to paint a
certain picture of the world if you
watch various listen to various analysts
they'll paint a certain picture of the
world the real world is
different the real to understand the
real world you have to go you to go
several layers deep and understand each
of these organizations how it was
created when was it created who created
it whose interest it
serves What policies does it Implement
and so on you have to go deep into all
these things to understand the true
purpose of an
organization when the IMF gives a loan
to a nation they don't simply give money
to the nation they also tell the nation
how to use the money how it will be used
and how it will not be used you become a
puppet once you get involved with the
World Bank in the
IMF so when you have the IMF bailing out
Pakistan over and over again it tells
you that Pakistan plays a significant
role in the service of the United States
of America now I hope that makes it
clear why the IMF keeps bailing out
Pakistan because Pakistan is a is an
important tool it's an important
asset that the US has what is the
purpose of Pakistan it's to keep India
under check and to keep dangling that
sword over India's head that you have
this Dr Rogue Nation to your West and
they have
nukes that sort of thing please
understand that's that's how the world
Works in in the real world that's how it
works
okay Krish Agarwal says do you
think can China start a war with India
at any moment what are its geopolitical
angles look it's a good question yes we
we should certainly take this question
so let's uh take a look once again at
the
map where is China where is India so
today you have India and China sharing a
sharing a border common border
historically see China has existed for
how long 3,000 years three and a half
thousand years if you want to be nice to
them India and China never had a common
border we always had this nation of
Tibet in in the Central Asian region and
China was east of the so-called Great
Wall of China which is way way way
further east from where China today is
so so India and China never had any
issues because of that after the 1950s
when Mr nehu the great magnificent Mr
Neu allowed the Chinese to take over
Tibet we have this issue this problem
this undemarcated border and this common
border when two major giant Nations have
a common border there's going to be
problems and China is currently please
understand more powerful significantly
more powerful than India China is three
to four times more powerful than India
right now the only thing that's holding
China
back okay from a realistic perspective
is the prospect of Indian nuclear
weapons the Chinese have spent decades
building up their economic power and if
they cross certain red lines of India
they stand to lose
everything so because of that that's one
factor and the other factor is the
incredibly inhospitable terrain of the
Himalayan
region extremely inhospitable
inhospitable terrain very very high
altitude terrain it's hard to just stand
and breathe there I've been there I've
reported from there you can see some
videos it's really really hard to be
there to just walk there it's almost
impossible to fight hand to hand and the
terrain is such that you can't do
conventional Warfare you have to do hand
to hand fighting often you can't it's
very inhospitable for armored vehicles
it's very hard for tanks to exist in
this terrain uh
it's hard for the Chinese to to you know
have planes fighter planes take off from
Tibet because it's such high altitude
and so on they can take off but they
will have to carry a lower lighter
payload and less arms and ammunition so
on because of all these factors it
doesn't make sense for China to start a
war with India they can certainly use
proxies like the disaster situation in
Burma to destabilize India they can
certainly use a nation like Pakistan
against India they can medal in the
Affairs of internal affairs of Nepal
they can meddle in the internal affairs
of the Maldives they can try to you know
coers Bangladesh or they can try to do
the debt trap diplomacy with Sri Lanka
they can keep on doing this but it
doesn't make sense for them if they have
any any sense to start a war with
India okay it could end up being a
complete disaster for China and China is
a different kind of country it's not a
democratic Nation it's a dictatorship in
China they don't tolerate a leader who
loses if you lose a war if you end up
starting a war that humiliates your
nation by not achieving the objectives
then you will be thrown out of power and
you will disappear into
nothingness you'll be instantaneously
ousted in a coup or or worse so because
of all these factors it doesn't make
sense for China to start a war with
India at this moment or any moment and
India is only getting more and more
powerful you wait a decade it will be a
different kind of India you wait two
decades it will be a whole different
India and China is tearing down at a
demographic
disaster the the falling birth rates the
falling falling TFR the Contracting
economy it's not going to be good for
China this this Century it's not the
Chinese Century yeah so that's the deal
so it doesn't make sense from a
realistic perspective for China to start
a war with India obviously China would
want India to disintegrate the only
nation in Eurasia apart from Russia that
China is concerned about that China
fears in the long run is India China has
three major adversaries the US Russia
and India and indiaan Russia are kind of
on the same page Russia very wants very
much wants India to get more grow more
powerful because India is by no means a
threat for Russia or India is a great
counterbalance towards for China from
the Russian perspective
and from the American perspective as
well which is so strange that Russia and
America agree about India from this
perspective so it's a complex situation
but overall I would say it doesn't make
sense for China to start a war with
India it would be it can end up as a
tremendous disaster for
China all right
um Firefly YT says what do you think
happened to DB Cooper
so this was sometime in the' 60s '70s
50s I don't remember which decade but
there was this guy in the US I think in
the
70s ' 70s was it shall we just Google it
this guy jumped off a plane and
apparently survived so let's uh go to
Google our friend Google DB
Cooper DB
[Music]
Cooper so which year was this 1971 it
was okay so this gentleman he boards an
aircraft okay he boards an aircraft and
in the US a commercial passenger plane
and in the middle of the plane I think
he he has stolen some money he's got a
whole bunch of cash apparently and he
asks one of the air hostesses he he
hijacks the plane he has all the
passengers disembark from some some
airport then he takes the plane off
again into the air he obviously tells
the pilots to take off and then at some
point in time he goes to the back door
in those days one of this aircraft used
to have a door in the back and he opens
the door and jumps off he has a
parachute and he's never
found some of that money was found later
at different points in time over the
years some money was found in in a river
or a stream some money was found
elsewhere but all the money wasn't
traced and the guy was never identified
he was never caught now I have a well
not a friend but I know this guy his
name is Chael sunen he's a MMA fighter
so let me put Uncle cha on the
screen cha
sonen this guy uh one of the MMA Legends
mixed martial arts Legends so this guy
claims that DB Cooper was his uncle one
of his uncles or someone he knew that's
what he claims but cha we know that he
has this habit of he has this P for
hyper balll and making tall stories very
entertaining guy but he claims that DB
Cooper was his uncle so we don't know so
it's a mystery we don't know what
happened to him but it looks like he got
away with it and he was successful in
not just hijacking the plane but getting
away with all that money
anyway some Mysteries may never Shale
sunnen never lost a round absolutely he
never lost a round tremendous guy
terrific
guy
ishan Pak says what's the situation in
Manipur right now I have heard and saw a
video where that cookie terrorists were
stopping Indian army Convoy the cookies
have like I said the situation has
happened over almost a century it is the
fault of the Indian governments post
1947 post 1949 when Manipur became part
of India officially they have let the
situation go out of control completely
they never fence the border and today
you have cookie
infiltrators who have overrun the
southern half of Manipur more than the
southern half of Manipur more than 50%
of the territory of man of Manipur if
you look at satellite images of the past
5 seven years you will see thousands of
new Villages coming up in Manipur in the
forests and the hills of Manipur they
have completely overrun the
place to solve this problem is going to
take
time this problem has happened over
decades and decades over more than a
century actually the British start they
planted the seeds of this nor of This
Disaster and the clueless Indian
governments starting from Mr neu's
government they just let the situation
run
unchecked and today we have the
situation this is a
geopolitical problem for India it's not
some random ragtag half naked Outsiders
who have come into India yes they are
they are ragtag Outsiders infiltrators
but they are all somehow coordinated and
controlled from
somewhere okay so this is a huge problem
for for India and for Burma and the root
cause is in
Myanmar and it's not a difficult thing
for India to go and cross the border and
solve the problem or whatever is
happening but it's not that easy either
the moment you do that the Americans
will step into the picture and they'll
say that India is now becoming an
expansionist Nation like Russia with
Ukraine so right
now unfortunately we'll have to bide our
time the first step is to start fencing
the border which will take years but you
going to start somewhere and there's
going to be resistance from within from
without and so on so yes the cookie
terrorists are are firing Rockets
they're fighting at Farmers they're
doing they're just you know rampaging
across the place there is no Law and
Order in that region where the cookie
terrorists are have set up their
Villages thousands of villages all
Outsiders all
foreigners okay so yeah it's it's
a bad situation right
now uh
India and Manipur in particular will
have to swallow some pain for a long
time but hopefully things will get
better and the indigenous people of
India will get Justice not the
foreigners who cares about them out go
back and these cookies are not even
Burmese by the way they don't speak the
Burmese language they don't practice
burmes culture they don't even respect
the burmes nation they came from Yan in
China a few few centuries ago maybe 300
years ago or 400 years ago but now there
their so-called Scholars are rewriting
history they are in jnu and what what
not we have given them privileges in our
nation so yeah that's the deal right now
with the with with
Manipur okay let's take one more
question we have crossed two hours we
have crossed two hours but let's take
one more
question somebody asked me a good
question
uh okay PES Das says why did Iraq really
invade Kuwait what were they trying to
achieve did they seriously believe they
could defeat the
US you see there was something called
the Iran Iraq war in the
1980s today you have a conflict in
Ukraine it is a proxy war between Russia
and the US and the US proxy is Ukraine
the Americans will fight this war until
the last Ukrainian is
alive similarly there was a proxy war in
the 1980s the Iran Iraq war Iraq was a
proxy of the US the Americans wanted to
destroy Iran and they ended up ruining
both Nations the outcome of the war was
a stalemate nobody won nobody lost but
both Nations suffered
horribly and the US puppet so to say was
Saddam Hussein
Saddam Hussein he he ran a tight ship in
his country he did a great job
administering his country and he
believed that he had the blessings of
the superpower the US and he could do
whatever he want let me try and grab
some more territory so Kuwait and Ira
Iraq are neighboring Nations and there
are oil wells massive oil wells in this
region and the Iraqis were alleging that
Kuwait was you know Going Underground
and and tapping oil from Iraqi Reserves
and that was the The Grudge that the
Iraqis had so Saddam Hussein asked the
Americans do you would you be okay if I
went ahead and solve this problem and
the Americans gave him the green light
they said go ahead you do that the
moment he does this the Americans
send this Invasion
Force so they clearly had decided the
Americans that it is time for Saddam
Hussein to be cut down to size so they
made him believe that they were okay
with his invasion of Kuwait and then
they used that as a pretext to destroy
his nation and they eventually you know
what they did to him so that's what
happened he did not believe that Saddam
husin did not believe that he could
defeat the US he believed he they he had
their blessing they fooled him as they
have fooled so many people in the
past all right with that we come to the
end of today's ask Abhijit episode
episode 173 thank you so much for
watching I'm going to end here uh and
I'll see you very soon in the next
episode until then take care wherever
you are have a good day good night keep
raising your standards thank you bye
until next time